Von Drehle, David; Papers apap213
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
David Von Drehle Papers
1897-2003
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Von Drehle, David, 1961-
apap213
7.5 cubic ft.
The David Von Drehle Papers contain information on the death penalty, primarily in Florida. Von Drehle compiled the materials while researching his 1995 book Among the Lowest of the Dead: Inside Death Row.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Acquisition Information
David Von Drehle donated his papers to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections at the State University of New York, Albany in 2005 and 2007.
Biographical Sketch
David Von Drehle was born in Denver, Colorado on February 6, 1961; he now resides in Shawnee Mission, Kansas. He is married to Karen Ball and they have four children, Henry, Ella, Addie, and Clara. Before attending college Von Drehle secured a job as a reporter at the Denver Post. At the age of seventeen he was the youngest sports writer in the paper’s history. He attended the University of Denver, receiving a Bachelor of Arts degree with double honors in English and Philosophy. Von Drehle continued his education at Oxford University, graduating with a Master of Letters in 1985.
After college he became a staff writer for The Miami Herald, receiving the Livingston Award for National Reporting, American Society of Newspaper Editors Distinguished Writing Award, and the American Bar Association Silver Gavel during his tenure at the paper. Von Drehle left The Miami Herald in 1991 to become senior writer and eventually assistant managing editor at The Washington Post. Currently Von Drehle is editor-at-large for TIME, a position he has held since 2007.
Von Drehle is also an author of four books, Among the Lowest of the Dead: Inside Death Row (1995), Deadlock: The Inside Story of America’s Closest Election (2001), Triangle: The Fire That Changed America (2003), and Rise to Greatness: Abraham Lincoln and American’s Most Perilous Year (2012). Von Drehle has also been a board member of many community organizations, including his current role as a director of the Youth Ambassadors of Kansas City and the Truman Library Institute.
Scope and Contents
David Von Drehle is an award winning journalist. He is the author of several books including 1985's Among the Lowest of the Dead: Inside Death Row, the book this collection is based upon. Among the Lowest of the Dead: Inside Death Row is described as: “Perhaps the finest book ever written on the death penalty” by the Chicago Tribune. The Von Drehle Papers contain all of the research material used to write this book, including correspondence, newspaper clippings, interview notes, law review articles, court appeals, and copies of inmate letters and diaries. It also features newspaper cover stories about the death penalty, including articles written by Von Drehle.
Among the Lowest of the Dead: Inside Death Row highlights faults in the capital punishment system not only in Florida, but throughout the country. Through in-depth interviews, review of famous cases and over ten years of research, Von Drehle hoped to capture a true picture of death row.
This collection is organized alphabetically by subject. Not all dates in the collection are inclusive. Cases of possible interest involving the death penalty within the Von Drehle Papers include Ted Bundy, William Jent, Ernest Miller, John Spenkelink, Robert Sullivan, and Arthur Goode. The collection also provides an overview of capital punishment in Florida.
The archivist retained the original order of Von Drehle's record keeping scheme. Therefore please note that case files, such as Willie Darden's, also include materials about other court cases involving related subjects or circumstances. Von Drehle also created Florida specific subject files, and then separate general folders on the same topic.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is arranged alphabetically. There are no series.
Death Penalty; Criminal Justice and Prisons; Capital punishment--Florida.; Death row inmates--Florida--Case studies.; Depositions; Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence; Notes; Transcripts; Files by subject; Von Drehle, David, 1961-; Bundy, Ted-; Darden, Willie Jasper, -1988; Graham, Bob, 1936-; United States. Supreme Court.; Florida. Supreme Court.; NAACP Legal Defense and Educational Fund.
- A-Leads to file, 1990-1994; Undated (Box 1 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 1)
- Abolition Study Commission, ca. 1963-1965 (Box 1 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 2)
- Abolition attempts, 1977; 1979 (Box 1 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 3)
- A.D. Adams - execution, 1989 (Box 1 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 4)
- A.D. Adams - family, 1986; Undated (Box 1 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 5)
- A.D. Adams - litigation, 1984; 1986; 1989; Undated (Box 1 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 6)
- A.D. Adams - mitigation, 1986 (Box 1 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 7-8)
- A.D. Adams - mitigation, 1989; 1987; 1991-1993 (Box 1 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 9)
- Adams, James - chronology, Undated (Box 1 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 10)
- Adams, James - clemency, 1980; 1984 (Box 1 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 11)
- Adams, James - commentary, 1984 (Box 1 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 12)
- Adams, James - execution, 1984 (Box 1 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 13)
- Adams, James - innocence?, 1984; Undated (Box 1 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 14)
- Adams, James - interviews, Undated (Box 1 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 15)
- Adams, James - race, 1984 (Box 1 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 16)
- Alabama - overturn death penalty, 1980 (Box 1 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 17)
- Antone, Anthony - aftermath, 1984; Undated (Box 1 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 18)
- Antone, Anthony - case accounts, 1984 (Box 1 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 19)
- Antone, Anthony - execution, 1984; Undated (Box 1 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 20)
- Antone, Anthony - interviews, 1984; Undated (Box 1 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 21)
- Antone, Anthony - litigation/clemency, 1984 (Box 1 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 22)
- Antone, Anthony - protests, 1984; Undated (Box 1 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 23)
- Arango, Carlos, Undated (Box 1 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 24)
- Archives - directory, Undated (Box 1 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 25)
- Askew, Reubin [Gov], 1972; 1977-1978; Undated (Box 1 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 26)
- Attorney crisis, 1982; 1984-1985; 1994; Undated (Box 1 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 27)
- Attorney shortages, 1986-1988; 1990-1991; 1994; Undated (Box 1 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 28-29)
- Barclay v. Florida, 1982-1983 (Box 1 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 30)
- Barefoot v. Estelle (& companies), 1982 (Box 1 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 31)
- Barnard, Craig [Attorney], 1979; 1983; 1987-1989; Undated (Box 1 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 32)
- Bertolotti, Anthony, 1990; 2003 (Box 1 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 33)
- Bibliography, 1982; 1986; 1990-1991; Undated (Box 1 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 34)
- Block, Irwin [Attorney], Undated (Box 1 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 35)
- Bolender, Bernard, 1982 (Box 1 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 36)
- Booker, Stephen T., 1983; 1986; 1991 (Box 1 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 37)
- Booth v. Maryland, 1986; 1990 (Box 1 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 38)
- Bowers, Bill [death penalty abolitionist], Undated (Box 1 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 39)
- Branford, Vernon [D.O.C.], 1984 (Box 1 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 40)
- Brain research, 1985; Undated (Box 1 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 41)
- Brieghton, Dave, 1977-1979; Undated (Box 1 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 42)
- Brown, Joseph Green, 1983; 1987; Undated (Box 1 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 43)
- Brown v. Florida/Wanwright, 1977; 1980-1983; Undated (Box 1 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 44)
- Bundy - 1986, Undated (Box 1 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 45)
- Bundy - audio cassettes, Early life/Sheridan Street, Undated (Cassette 1-3)
- Bundy - audio cassettes, Aspen, Undated (Cassette 4-6)
- Bundy - audio cassettes, Verdicts, 1979-1980 (Cassette 7-11)
- Bundy - audio cassettes, Execution, Undated (Cassette 12)
- Bundy - chronologies, 1986; 1989; Undated (Box 1 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 46)
- Bundy - clips/media, 1979; 1987; 1989 (Box 1 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 47)
- Bundy - commentary, 1980; 1989 (Box 1 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 48)
- Bundy - confessions, 1989-1991; Undated (Box 1 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 49)
- Bundy - corpse photo, 1989; 1993 (Box 1 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 50)
- Bundy - daughter, 1981 (Box 1 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 51)
- Bundy - demonology, 1987; 1989-1991; Undated (Box 1 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 52)
- Bundy - Dobson, 1989-1990; Undated (Box 1 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 53)
- Bundy - escape attempt, 1984; Undated (Box 1 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 54)
- Bundy - execution, 1989 (Box 1 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 55)
- Bundy - family, 1989 (Box 1 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 56)
- Bundy - last appeals, 1988; Undated (Box 1 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 57)
- Bundy - last days, 1989; Undated (Box 1 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 58)
- Bundy - litigation (folders 1-2 of 11), 1982-1983; 1986-1989; Undated (Box 1 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 59-60)
- Bundy - litigation (folders 3-11 of 11), 1982-1983; 1986-1989; Undated (Box 2 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 1-9)
- Bundy -New York Times, 1986 (Box 2 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 10)
- Bundy - notes, Undated (Box 2 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 11)
- Bundy - psychology, 1979; 1988-1991; Undated (Box 2 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 12)
- Bundy - Tanner, 1989-1990; Undated (Box 2 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 13)
- Bundy - victims, 1989 (Box 2 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 14)
- Bundy - will, Undated (Box 2 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 15)
- Butterworth, Bob, 1986 (Box 2 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 16)
- Carter, Jimmy, 1987; 1990; Undated (Box 2 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 17)
- Cary, Susan [Attorney], Undated (Box 2 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 18)
- Cases - misc., 1988; 1991; Undated (Box 2 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 19)
- CCR - Capital Collateral Representative, 1985-1989; Undated (Box 2 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 20)
- Churches - other religious organizations, 1980-1981; 1983-1985; 1988; 1990; Undated (Box 2 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 21)
- Clark, Ramsey, 1971; Undated (Box 2 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 22)
- Clearinghouse, 1982; Undated (Box 2 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 23)
- Clemency - first 6, 1971; 1976-1977; 1979 (Box 2 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 24)
- Clemency - general, 1980-1983; 1986; Undated (Box 2 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 25)
- Coker v. Georgia, 1976 (Box 2 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 26)
- Coler, Daniel, 1980; 1982 (Box 2 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 27)
- Collins, LeRoy [Gov], 1979 (Box 2 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 28)
- Cooper, Vernon, 1977; 1989-1991; Undated (Box 2 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 29)
- Cost studies, 1982; 1987-1988; 1991; Undated (Box 2 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 30-31)
- Court overloads, 1981; 1987-1988; Undated (Box 2 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 32)
- Cover stories about the death penalty, including Von Drehle bylines, 1987-1989; 1991; Undated (Oversized 1)
- Crime rates/fear, 1980; 1982; 1990-1994; Undated (Box 2 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 33)
- Darden, Willie - case accounts, 1988 (Box 2 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 34)
- Darden, Willie - charisma, 1980-1981; 1985 (Box 2 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 35)
- Darden, Willie - chronology, Undated (Box 2 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 36)
- Darden, Willie - close calls, 1985; Undated (Box 2 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 37)
- Darden, Willie - commentary, 1991; Undated (Box 2 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 38)
- Darden, Willie - execution, 1988; Undated (Box 2 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 39)
- Darden, Willie - litigation/clemency, 1976; 1984-1985; 1988; Undated (Box 2 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 40)
- Darden, Willie - protests, 1988; Undated (Box 2 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 41)
- Darden, Willie - race, 1978; 1988; Undated (Box 2 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 42)
- Darden, Willie - victims, Undated (Box 2 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 43)
- Darden, Willie - writings, Undated (Box 2 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 44)
- Daugherty, Jeffery - execution, 1988 (Box 2 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 45)
- Death belt, 1985 (Box 2 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 46)
- Death penalty - analysis of failings, 1985; Undated (Box 2 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 47)
- Death penalty - cost, 1988; 1992; Undated (Box 2 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 48)
- Death penalty - general commentary, 1962; 1979; 1985-1986; 1988; Undated (Box 2 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 49)
- 18th-19th century death penalty - history, 1897; 1982; 1989; Undated (Box 2 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 50)
- 20th century death penalty- history, 1900-1942; 1964-1971; 1976-1977; 1982-1991; Undated (Box 3 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 1)
- Death penalty - national, 1985; 1987-1994; Undated (Box 3 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 2)
- Death penalty - international, 1981; 1991-1993 (Box 3 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 3)
- Death penalty - outlines, 1989 (Box 3 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 4)
- Death penalty - politics, 1984; 1988; 1990-1994; Undated (Box 3 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 5)
- Death penalty - seminars/education, 1983-1984; Undated (Box 3 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 6)
- Death penalty - statistics, 1984; 1987-1990; 1992-1994; Undated (Box 3 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 7)
- Death Row, Undated (Video-tape 1)
- Death Row - daily grind, 1967-1971; 1976-1977; 1980-1984; 1988-1989; Undated (Box 3 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 8)
- Death Row - Florida, 1980; Undated (Box 3 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 9)
- Death Row - inmate protests, 1975-1976; 1978-1980 (Box 3 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 10)
- Death Row - national, 1976-1979; 1981; 1989; 1992; Undated (Box 3 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 11)
- Death Row - rosters/population, 1976-1979; 1981-1984; 1994; Undated (Box 3 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 12)
- Death Row - suicides, 1975; 1982-1985; Undated (Box 3 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 13)
- Death Row - women, 1977; 1979; 1989-1990; Undated (Box 3 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 14)
- Death watch, 1984; 1986; Undated (Box 3 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 15)
- Defense tactics - trial, 1981; 1983-1984; 1993 (Box 3 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 16-17)
- Delay - examples, 1983; 1985; 1988; 1991-1992 (Box 3 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 18)
- Demps, Benny, 1981-1982; Undated (Box 3 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 19)
- Deterrence, 1980; 1983-1984; 1991; Undated (Box 3 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 20)
- Dobbert, Ernest - bio/case accounts, 1982 (Box 3 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 20)
- Dobbert, Ernest - child abuse, 1982; Undated (Box 3 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 21)
- Dobbert, Ernest - commentary, 1984; Undated (Box 3 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 22)
- Dobbert, Ernest - execution/last hours, 1984 (Box 3 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 23)
- Dobbert, Ernest - litigation/clemency, 1982; 1984; Undated (Box 3 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 24)
- Doherty, Pat [Attorney], 1982; 1984; Undated (Box 3 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 25)
- Domestic violence, Undated (Box 3 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 26)
- Dougan, Jacob, 1977; 1990; Undated (Box 3 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 27)
- Douglas, Howard, 1971; 1991; Undated (Box 3 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 28)
- Dugger, Richard [D.O.C.], 1979; 1982; 1984-1986; Undated (Box 3 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 29)
- Durocher, Michael - voluntary execution, 1993 (Box 3 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 30)
- Electric chair, 1979; 1990; 1992; Undated (Box 3 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 31)
- Electrocution - effects/procedures, 1983; 1990; Undated (Box 3 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 32-33)
- Eleventh Circuit - judges, 1990-1991 (Box 3 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 34)
- Emund v. Florida/Tison v. Arizona, 1981-1982; 1986; Undated (Box 3 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 35)
- Escapes, 1980; 1982-1983; Undated (Box 3 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 36)
- Executions - broadcasts/interviews, 1977; 1991; Undated (Box 3 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 37)
- Executions - chronologies, 1990; Undated (Box 3 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 38)
- Execution - technical/procedure, 1973; 1979; 1984-1989; 1990-1992; Undated (Box 3 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 39)
- Famous cases, 1985; Undated (Box 3 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 40)
- Farmer, Millard [Attorney], Undated (Box 3 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 41)
- Feamster, Tom, Undated (Box 3 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 42)
- Fins, Deborah [Attorney], Undated (Box 3 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 43)
- Fleming, Myron, Undated (Box 3 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 44)
- FL Governor's race '86, 1985-1986 (Box 3 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 45)
- FL Governor's Select Committee, 1972; Undated (Box 3 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 46)
- Florida - corrections, 1980; 1982-1983; 1986; 1989-1990; Undated (Box 3 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 47)
- Florida - legislation, 1967; 1972; 1980; Undated (Box 3 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 48)
- Florida - media coverage, 1985; 1990 (Box 3 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 49)
- Florida - overview, 1981; 1983; 1985; Undated (Box 3 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 50)
- Florida - rape provision, 1981-1982; Undated (Box 3 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 51)
- Florida -regional differences, 1979; 1982; 1986 (Box 3 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 52)
- Florida State Prison, 1980-1983; 1986; Undated (Box 3 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 53)
- Florida Supreme Court - cases, 1980-1981; 1989-1990; 1994; Undated (Box 3 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 54)
- Florida Supreme Court - justices, 1979; 1985-1988; Undated (Box 3 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 55)
- Florida Supreme Court - scene analysis, 1983; 1986; Undated (Box 3 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 56)
- Ford, Alvin, 1981-1982; 1984-1986; Undated (Box 3 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 57)
- Francis v. Resweber, 1946 (Box 3 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 58)
- Francois, Marvin - execution, 1985; Undated (Box 3 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 59)
- Funchess, David - case accounts, 1979; Undated (Box 3 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 60)
- Funchess, David - execution, 1986; Undated (Box 3 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 61)
- Funchess, David - PTSD, 1986; 1988; 1991; 1993; Undated (Box 3 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 62)
- Furman v. Georgia, 1971-1972; 1992; Undated (Box 3 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 63)
- Furman - reaction, 1972-1973; Undated (Box 4 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 1)
- Furman - survivors, Undated (Box 4 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 2)
- Gardner v. Florida, 1976 (Box 4 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 3)
- Georgieff, George [Attorney], 1963; 1967; 1974; 1981; Undated (Box 4 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 4)
- Gibson, Robin, Undated (Box 4 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 5)
- Gilmore, Gary - reaction, 1976-1977 (Box 4 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 6)
- Golstein, Steve, Undated (Box 4 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 7)
- Goode - case accounts, 1978; Undated (Box 4 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 8)
- Goode - commentary, 1982; 1984; Undated (Box 4 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 9)
- Goode - description/interviews, 1977-1980; 1982-1984; Undated (Box 4 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 10)
- Goode - execution, 1984; Undated (Box 4 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 11)
- Goode - family, 1982; 1984; 1991; Undated (Box 4 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 12)
- Goode - inmate hatred, 1977; Undated (Box 4 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 13)
- Goode - last hours, 1984 (Box 4 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 14)
- Goode - litigation/clemency, 1982-1984; Undated (Box 4 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 15)
- Goode - petitions, 1983; Undated (Box 4 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 16)
- Goode - sanity, 1977-1980; Undated (Box 4 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 17)
- Graham, Bob [Gov], 1977; 1979-1986; 1989; Undated (Box 4 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 18)
- Gregg v. Georgia, 1975; 1980; Undated (Box 4 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 19)
- Guided discretion - analysis, 1980; Undated (Box 4 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 20)
- Habeas reform, 1985-1986; 1988; 1990-1991; Undated (Box 4 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 21-22)
- Hall, Freddie Lee/Ruffin, Mark, 1982 (Box 4 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 23)
- Hallman, Clifford, 1977 (Box 4 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 24)
- Hamblen, James, 1988; 1990; Undated (Box 4 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 25)
- Harris, Robert, 1979; 1982; 1989-1990; Undated (Box 4 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 26)
- Harris, Robert - litigation/habeas corpus, 1990; Undated (Box 4 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 27-29)
- Harrison, Baya [Attorney], ca.1991-1986; Undated (Box 4 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 30)
- Henry, James - case accounts, Undated (Box 4 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 31)
- Henry, James - execution, 1984 (Box 4 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 32)
- Henry, James - race, 1984 (Box 4 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 33)
- Henry, James - victim, 1979 (Box 4 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 34)
- Hitchcock v. Dugger, 1978; 1983; 1986; 1991; Undated (Box 4 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 35)
- Holdman, Scharlette, 1979; 1981-1984; 1988-1989; Undated (Box 4 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 36)
- House Select Committee, 1972; Undated (Box 4 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 37)
- Hoy, Darrell, 1980 (Box 4 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 38)
- Hudson, Olliff [Judge], 1975; 1981; 1983; Undated (Box 4 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 39)
- Hull, Steve, ca. 1991-1986; Undated (Box 4 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 40)
- Ingle, Joe, Undated (Box 4 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 41)
- Innocence, 1987; 1989; 1992-1993; Undated (Box 4 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 42)
- Jent/Miller - aftermath, 1989; Undated (Box 4 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 43)
- Jent/Miller - appeals, 1981-1983; 1986-1987; Undated (Box 4 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 44)
- Jent/Miller - Armstrong, 1979; 1987 (Box 4 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 45-46)
- Jent/Miller - assorted police, 1978-1979; 1987; Undated (Box 4 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 47)
- Jent/Miller - autopsies, 1979; 1983; 1986; Undated (Box 4 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 48)
- Jent/Miller - Carroll, 1987; Undated (Box 4 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 49)
- Jent/Miller - case (folder 1 of 3), 1987; Undated (Box 4 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 50)
- Jent/Miller - case (folder 2-3 of 3), 1987; Undated (Box 5 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 1-2)
- Jent/Miller - clemency, 1983 (Box 5 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 3)
- Jent/ Miller - chronologies, 1987; Undated (Box 5 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 4)
- Jent/ Miller - clips/media, 1979-1980; 1983-1988; Undated (Box 5 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 5)
- Jent/ Miller - cops, 1979-1980; 1987; Undated (Box 5 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 6)
- Jent/Miller - Dalton, 1985-1988; Undated (Box 5 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 7)
- Jent/Miller - Dodd, 1986-1987; Undated (Box 5 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 8)
- Jent/Miller - Elmer/Tina, 1980; 1983-1984; Undated (Box 5 (David Von Drehle Papers ), Folder 9-10)